well that was ominous that was an
ominous start to the episode I didn't
even I didn't even start my intro so
remember last episode there was lots of
parrots or chickens all over the shop
and I lost them I thought they'd all
gone well I found them for some reason
they're all chilling in here I thought
they were lost forever but no they're
pretty much all just gone in the various
villager cubby holes it's like they've
all got their own little pack so what I
thought I'd do is I'd try and get some
of these out of here with a lead does
this even work and we'll kick off today
whoa and we'll kick off today fight
someone's up to their own challenges by
doing some hermit charits I mean
challenges give a present to Mumbo okay
well there's one what else have we got
in here I can't actually get to them I
have to try and fly in this hole uh we
can
give a present to iskau where did that
other chicken just go I can't I can't
leave these alone for two seconds
where's he gone he's literally run off
and vanished oh there he is
give a present to Mumbo and give a
present to iskau hmm
well this gives me
an idea so they gave me a giant chicken
slash parrot charit thing whatever this
thing is and I also I have no idea what
to do with this I'm gonna leave it there
for now I say we pull an UNO reverse
card on Mumbo and iscal give a present
to Mumbo give a present to iscal I say
what we do is we go straight over to
their bases we like go somewhere in
between the two bases and we give them a
taste of their own medicine I think we
should put a quite literal Uno reverse
card they're gonna give me a bunch of
nonsensical hermit Challengers I'm gonna
give them a bunch of a nonsensical
hermit Challengers the plan is so
dastardly unoriginal that it's perfect
so somewhere between the two
would be here let's make it nice and
obvious to both of them where we're
going to put this
I actually had to go and think about it
for a second so I went and I got some
concrete and all the bits that I need
and I've actually designed something so
let's get cracking we are going to need
a platform in the air that Mumbo and
iscal can stand on
and also I've tried to make it as close
to in between these two so both people
can see it the idea is pretty simple we
have an UNO reverse card or as close to
an UNO reverse card as I can make
floating here in the sky and on the
inside of the card is going to be a
bunch of renamed chickens then when they
arrive what they'll find is a button on
this platform they press the button the
card Falls the chickens come out
everyone gets challenged this is going
to take a wee bit of engineering to get
done I think it's probably best if we
time lapse this because it's going to
take a little while so let's hope that
this all works and let's get cracking
foreign
[Music]
I'm not sure you would know what this is
until you're told it might look familiar
it might look like a picture of a
football an American football that is
but the second that I tell you that this
is an UNO reverse card you can see it
you can definitely see it a bit more
when you're further away that's just the
limitations of pixel art in Minecraft it
looks much better from afar if you ask
me but either way when Mumbo and iskal
see this they come over here and they
see my sign it says as per the challenge
here is a present for Mumbo and iskau
and then there's a mysterious button
here now I actually need to check if
this works because otherwise it's going
to be really embarrassing for everyone
I've kind of winged it I okay it's very
simple Redstone but we're gonna try I
haven't put any chicken challenges in
there this is just to make sure it works
and then we'll have to reset it so three
two one boom
yes
it works ABS spots on so the chickens
will then fall down from there and then
they'll get stuck in this lovely place
here now the chickens might fall down in
here that's why I've left a sign that's
somewhere somewhere around here
somewhere around here there we go this
box was designed to keep your chickens
nice and safe just because I uh yeah I'm
not mine Minecraft expert I couldn't I
couldn't figure out anything else but I
think this works this definitely works
and now we've got to reset the whole
thing but it says here hermit challenge
is yay initiation Etc and stuff they say
words and then it means hermit
challenges so I'm just getting in on
that your present is an original concept
chicken challenges it's up to you who
does which challenge Uno reverse card so
let's get this set up again really
quickly and skedaddle out of here before
one or the other of them turn up and
ruin it all the Pistons essentially
really push the scaffolding and then it
all breaks and then of course this falls
down and bingo bango all the chickens
are let loose there we go all reset the
final piece of the puzzle is to get the
chickens in here and it's a good job I
came prepared with eggs that was 32 eggs
and one chicken I just want to point
that out I guess I need to start
thinking about some challenges so 32
eggs and you get one chicken
another 16 and you get like six
maths there we go that's a that's a
fairly decent amount of chickens but I
think we've got to go a bit more
overboard okay I've brought five anvils
with me and now I need to come up with
enough challenges to keep Mumbo and
iskau busy for at least a few episodes
just like they've done to me of course I
have no levels back to the trading Hall
I go okay got 20 levels
and now we need to start coming up with
some challenges now I don't actually
know all the challenges they've given me
so there might actually be some repeats
that would be really funny so we'll see
how I like our minds are so let me think
like how crazy can I go use someone
else's intro
I have far too many chickens
Caleb with someone and say nothing
can you imagine just recording with
someone else on the server and you just
don't say anything
only turn left
let me turn left
for three minutes
is the really simple things can you
imagine like I can't okay so if I want
to turn right I have to do that every
time
I refer to yourself in the third person
[Laughter]
it's up to them how long they want to do
it for to be fair I'm trying to think
what they gave me obviously they had
each other to bounce off of I I just I'm
just doing this solo I'm just sort of
thinking what would be quite funny where
A hermits skin and follow them attempt
to sell your face to someone I have to
use occasionally I have to use like text
language to make sure it fits on there
imagine that like they can don't get me
wrong this one attempt to sell your base
to someone Mumbo can be like ah do you
wanna you wanna buy my base he could he
could sell it for like 10 million
diamonds he just he just has to try and
convince someone to buy it okay I'm not
gonna I'm gonna keep going but I'm not
going to reveal what all of them are
because I want some of them to be a bit
of a surprise I've just I've been
spending like half an hour just coming
up with ideas I don't know if all of
these will even work oh
replace the diamond throne with mycelium
replace the diamond throne with basilia
that's gonna stir up some
trucks okay okay okay I'm gonna do this
off camera now they're all named all
inside the Uno reverse card ready to be
deployed job is done and we should go
because I want to check up on one of the
more exciting things going on in the
server in my opinion or at least ones
that involve me the mycelium little Turf
War resistance thing that's going on I'm
gonna go and see if I can build it a
little bit bigger free samples and a
button bro you don't need to put free
samples I'll press the button congrats
on your free glass okay well thank thank
you for the thank you for the glass it's
a bit weird over here it doesn't look
like the establishment has got rid of it
just yet and it is is creeping out I
think I think we should uh make this a
bit more insane they've got their own
Highway we can make the mycelium highway
I'm thinking we need to like link these
two up and I keep having to go over here
this is like the only place that's
actually got mycelium left now I need to
make sure I actually have a supply of
mycelium because if this if this area
actually gets used for something in the
future I'm gonna lose my my Supply why
can't I pick these up is there lag bruh
what's going oh no
okay I think I understand the glass
thing now that gray glass is the exact
same color
as my inventory
that's that's devious
what did I think of that that's genius
soon the entire shopping district
is going to be covered in the fungi that
is mycelium
there we go there we go it's starting to
spread and we'll make another patch as
well somewhere over here just start to
get the guys on hermitcraft panicking
and interested in the mycelium movement
is quite literally a movement and I also
had a fantastic idea on how to kind of
recruit people to the movement so in the
barge I was gonna give some resistance
um
ha nice
um yes burn sticks I have been Rose
bushed I think I've been pranked but I'm
not quite sure well obviously I've been
pranked but what does this mean what did
I do to deserve this the barge has been
an innocent bystander okay we're getting
we're getting rid of these roses
this is insane
what is
hello
oh it's honey
oh my goodness that was the weirdest
thing
there's um there's a honey bee hive
there gross leaving a mess this is it
this is actually quite insane that's a
lot of rose bushes is this because like
I is this because I refuse to pay the
mayor money I mean I vote I voted for
him what more does he want from me
diamonds honestly the mayor the last
thing the mayor needs on this server is
more diamonds oh there's straight up
bees just flying around
I kind of like the bees actually look
the mystery boxes are all gone well at
least I I hope they are look there we go
over two in his half stacks of diamonds
the joke's on you I'm now selling these
rose bushes in the barge same with the
grass thank you very much for the stock
that means I now need more mystery boxes
they take too long to make there we go
our Diamond pile is looking a bit more
healthy from the the Treasure Island
incident we may even be where we started
so my plan to recruit people to the
mycelium resistance is really simple and
hopefully quite effective
because what I plan on doing is selling
mycelium selling mycelium and then we're
going to have a hopper underneath this
chest and whenever someone purchases
mycelium which indicates to me that they
are an ally in the movement because you
know no one's going to buy mycelium
unless they're wanting to sort of spread
it around the server so you pop your
diamond in there'll be a hopper it then
detects it and opens up the mycelium
resistance headquarters so that's what
we need to make now
by digging underneath the barge I don't
know how deep we want to go for this
thing
we got a what what on Earth is this
under the barge I'm scared someone's
beating me to building a secret thing
under the barge not good
oh it's massive
okay
we'll um
we'll make we'll just make our thing
on top of this thing I've no this is
clearly quite a big project that I've
stumbled upon and I'm not sure what it
is but we're not going to interrupt it
but this is technically land owned by me
so I'm still gonna use this land
underneath the barge so let's Hollow
this out and get something made
foreign
[Music]
a couple of hours later it's here
selling mycelium for two diamonds now
that sounds very expensive and it is
intentionally so that we only attract
people that truly want to join the
resistance so again it was two hours and
a couple of lessons from R1 and only
who gave me a short basically a tutorial
on how to do whatever's going on here
with The Observers and the one tick
triple piston extender I was able to
make the item detection because it's
going to detect diamonds going in I was
able to do that and I was able to make
the piston door work but I wasn't able
to put them together and make them work
in the same space so iscal thank you so
much for that now let's test it out we
put two diamonds in
boom
see look at that Flawless clean smooth
and we're in to the resistance HQ it's
not an awful lot at the moment now what
I tried to do was have like tunnels I
wanted to make it look like this place
was spreading underground which it kind
of is but I wanted to have like dark
tunnels where it looks like it just
extends across the shopping district
we've got our meeting table for just me
and of course we're growing some fungi
and I've added a couple of signs welcome
to the resistance we need you to
continue the turf war and keep mycelium
alive in the district I feel like what I
really need is an area where we can
place dirt and basically Farm lots of
mycelium so that I don't have to keep
stealing it from the only stronghold of
it left but here we are the mycelium
resistance headquarters I need to add
some more here but I'm not entirely sure
what this is as deep as I can go because
literally just underneath me oh dang it
uh is is this so we're a bit limited
more limited than I wanted to be on this
and then if you want to get out that get
getting out is actually cheaper than
getting in
uh there's just a secret trapdoor that
leads out here that I don't think anyone
will find now as we saw earlier there
was some honey boxes here now I bet
actually never drank a bottle of honey
in Minecraft what I wasn't expecting was
you know how you drink a potion in fact
let's go and drink one right now oh
looks like stress didn't pay either look
here's a here's a potion it makes the
most horrible Minecraft noise right like
oh I drank it
dang it now I gotta pay for it you drink
it you pay for it ah I'm out of diamonds
no I'm out of diamonds okay it's one
diamond for three I'll just put a stack
of emeralds in there that that'll do so
as I'm saying it's the
potion and then this is what honey
sounds like
arguably arguably more disgusting in my
opinion it sounds like you're like
gargling like
foreign
makes me gag it makes me feel sick
I don't know I really don't like that
sound effects it's really grim
suspicious
the law enforcement is out and about so
the turf war continues we've made a
bridge hopefully we can make a mycelium
highway but what we're really waiting to
see is how Scar and his enforcer are
gonna react to the fact that there's
this giant living piece of mycelium that
is crawling over the shopping district
because I can't imagine it's going to be
a particularly good reaction now we need
to head over to the upside down really
quickly because I heard the B-Dubs has
done an awful lot of work and I really
want to see and it turns out that scar
has broken the rules whoa
how how have they done this
how did they put the text upside down
the upside down
now entrance now enter now entering the
upside down okay that took me a little
bit longer than I thought whoa
whoa this car has been busy
scar has been so busy this looks amazing
it looks like he's actually Excavating
all of this stuff that isn't going to
stop the fact that he's on Tunnel Duty
for a long time here's the evidence of
what he did check out this little clip
here I did some serious AFK up at
Green's Mansion there and he's built
this I don't care I don't care he still
break the rules and all and there's a
new rule all entering then upside down
must appear upside down ah poop we
better get upside down fortunately for
me I'm always prepared check it out
there's nothing unusual here nothing
unusual at all I think there's a bit of
my hair still up there
hello
this is this is some cursed Minecraft
right here
hello
so what I wanted to see that looks like
potentially a spoiler free sample
courtesy of impulse I better check if
this is a spoiler wall of some kind or
he did this to protect himself from gas
cdubs has confirmed that I can go and
have a little look
my goodness doesn't look like the
ceiling is done
but that's not necessarily a bad thing
because we need to open that up with
some TNT Shenanigans I didn't bring
why do I always do this look at look at
the state of my inventory a bit of wood
a couple of eggs and some empty bottles
why am I never prepared I'm supposed to
be a professional oh my face is gone
this is looking pretty cool I can't wait
to see the final product and indeed I
encourage you to go to B-Dubs Channel
when his video comes out and hopefully
he'll have the whole thing So the plan
is maybe next episode we open that up we
actually make our Pigman Farm we get
this thing rolling and then we create a
proper gold Farm or at least that is the
plan make this thing really really
functional aha here is scars upside down
drill I love the fact that everything's
upside down including the inside so scar
car
you went AFK in my base
30 minutes tunnel Duty
improve the tunnel
with ice
you're on Tunnel Duty for breaking the
rules now with that all said and done I
don't really like talking with my feet
but unfortunately that is all I have
time for today it might seem like the
videos are coming a little bit slower
than usual and that is the case I am
actually getting married very soon in
fact this week and my time has been
almost entirely taken up with planning
and preparations and I actually did
another secret thing that you won't know
about until October so my time has been
strained maybe I shouldn't talk with my
feet maybe I should talk down down here
oh my wife I almost lost my lunch oh
jeez okay now we can talk I almost
walked off the edge that would have been
the end of me so
it's ridiculous so I have been extremely
busy and just a little bit longer a
little bit more patience because in a
couple of weeks everything will go back
to normal and we should be back on it
with the hermitcraft shenanigans so I
want to say a big thank you and just
thank you for being patient as well it's
been pretty stressful time recently and
it's a miracle that I managed to get
anything done seriously I finished a
video and I think yeah cool I'm done for
like I'm done for it I can relax I can
get some stuff done for a couple of days
I blink and then it's been five days
it's literally that is exactly how it
goes I blink and it's five days okay I
think I think I think this is where I'm
gonna have to say goodbye look into my
eyes not my feet the goodbyes goodbye